Dalvan Carvalho

Front-End Developer

IT specialist with over 10 years of experience in the technology field, looking to leverage research and problem-solving skills in front-end development. Values collaboration with teams that share knowledge and ideas in development, design, and user experience.

Contact

contact@dalvanc.com

+5592 98551-8435

in linkedin.com/in/dalvancarvalho

github.com/dalvancarvalho

dalvanc.com

RS, Brazil (UTC -03:00)

Skills

Programming languages

HTML JavaScript
CSS TypeScript

Sass

Libraries and frameworks

React GSAP

Next.js Framer Motion

Tailwind CSS Chart.js

Tools, platforms and others

Git Vercel GitHub Figma

PostgreSQL

Professional experience

Front-End Developer

08/2022 - Present

 Develops responsive websites and applications (compatible with mobile devices) using modern CSS frameworks and JavaScript libraries like Tailwind CSS and React.

- Stays updated with the latest trends and technologies in front-end development, following best practices and prioritizing the **maintainability and scalability** of applications.
- Develops and implements interfaces with a focus on enhancing the user experience (UX) by utilizing component-based architectures, resulting in a modular and reusable front-end solution.
- Utilizes **REST APIs** to create web applications, ensuring an efficient data retrieval and interaction with back-end services.

Coordinator

Topocart \cdot 07/2019 — 08/2021 \cdot Manaus, AM



dalvan c_

- Led office teams in Manaus and Brasília (the latter remotely) for the successful execution of tasks in projects across different locations in the country, contributing to operational efficiency and goal achievement.
- Used Jenkins to automate repetitive tasks, ensuring that the team always had up-to-date material to perform analyses, improving process efficiency and result accuracy.
- Ensured stability and efficiency of the IT infrastructure in the Manaus office by **leading the** management and maintenance of workstations, servers, and storage in close collaboration with the company's IT team at the headquarters in Brasília.

Research and Mapping Agent \cdot 05/2017 - 07/2019 \cdot Santa Cruz do Sul, RS

- Utilized database management systems like PostgreSQL to handle the data collected throughout the project, creating queries that facilitated analysis and made comparison with the database provided by the client more efficient.
- Facilitated efficient communication between the company and the client, actively participating
 in weekly alignment meetings, ensuring a harmonious collaboration aligned with the project
 objectives.

IT Technician

IDB Informática · 01/2012 - 05/2017



- Led the technical support department **for over 5 years**, excelling in providing remote and onsite technical support to end users. Additionally, trained new technicians and implemented methods for detecting and resolving issues at both software and hardware levels.
- Performed on-site maintenance and management of IT and network infrastructure for corporate clients, significantly optimizing issue resolution. Ensured personalized assistance, precisely aligned with the individual needs of each case, resulting in more efficient infrastructure management and lasting customer satisfaction.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering – BE, Civil Engineering

University of Santa Cruz do Sul - UNISC

2018

• The Creative JavaScript Course

• The Creative React Course

· SQL and Database

Languages

Portuguese

Native

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Spanish

Limited Working Proficiency

Interests

- Tech
- Urbanism
- Design
- Music
- Photography
- Sports